RICH JEN

Atlanta, GA • rich.rjen@gmail.com

Versatile, well-rounded IT professional with broad experience in quality assurance, automation, penetration testing, networking, and sales. Senior technical resource within both startup (Ionic Security) and established companies (IBM, Nan Ya Plastics, and Red Hat). Effective in bridging the gap between developers, engineers, sales, customer support, and clients. Tenacious troubleshooter, adept at quickly assessing situations, finding loopholes, and selecting the right course of action for rapid resolution. A former industrial engineering project manager with strong training, mentoring, and project management skills.

PROFESSIONAL WORK HISTORY

Red Hat, Atlanta, GA, 09/2017 - Present

Software Engineer in Test

Test and support a web application that is developed and used internally Develop Javascript, HTML, Apache Velocity based reports

Skill set Used: Python, Selenium, Java, Javascript, HTML, SQL

Manheim, Atlanta, GA, 08/2015 – 09/2017

Test Automation Engineer

Assist in testing a search API. Write test automation code and contribute to a current test automation framework. Managing a deployment pipeline.

Test frontend and backend of a search API.

Skill set Used: Ruby, SQL, Cucumber, Jenkins, Javascript, Webdriverio, Selenium

Ionic Security, Atlanta, GA, 04/2013 - 08/2015

QA Engineer / Sales Engineer

Perform QA on a data security product that interacts and leverages SaaS web applications and mobile apps. Primarily worked on automation in an agile environment while performing manual testing and exploratory testing. Develop and execute test plans, cases, strategies, and scenarios for performance, regression, and smoke testing on Windows XP/7/8, Linux, MacOS, IE 8-11, Chrome, and Firefox platforms. Facilitate communications between engineering and customer support teams.

Support Account Managers in removing friction from the sale. Giving sales demonstrations of a SaaS security product.

Skill set Used: Java, Ruby, Selenium, Cucumber, SQL, Watir-webdriver, Appium, C#, .Net, and Python

Key Achievements:

- Rapidly learned and applied emerging technologies to test and deploy over 400 releases.
 - Acquired proficiency in automation technology: Selenium WebDriver, Cucumber and Appium.
 - Proficient in writing Java, Ruby, Python, Javascript, VB, and Bash scripts to execute automation testing and a variety of automated tasks.
- Entrusted to manage all Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) initiatives
- Integral in setting up Bamboo and Jenkins continuous integration servers.
 - Stood up a Selenium Grid with 50 VMs used for parallel and distributed testing.
 - Added machines into CI process to automate testing of mobile devices (iPad, iPhone).
- Played key role in establishing entire SDLC process from development to production.
- Built and maintained testing frameworks for Java/TestNG (Selenium), Ruby/Cucumber (Selenium), Ruby/Stir (REST Services), and JRuby/Appium (Android, iOS).

RICH JEN PAGE 2 OF 2

- Tasked with setting up a server that unifies the testing framework results into one place, along with manual testing results (manual tests from Test Rail, Ruby, Java).
- Assumed control of setting up support platform for DevOps, managing eight high availability servers, and troubleshooting complex issues.

IBM Security Systems, Atlanta, GA, 01/2011 – 04/2013

Level 2 Software Support Engineer

Provided expert technical guidance to Fortune 500, federal government, and US military clients worldwide in strategically planning and implementing their security infrastructure architecture. Recommended, customized, implemented, and troubleshooted IBM Security products including SiteProtector, GX Network IPS, Enterprise Scanner, and Proventia Server. Core member of high-volume global support team, handling an average of 80 tickets monthly and resolving 90% of customer issues via phone or email.

- Performed network traffic/data analyses and network security risk management (damage control).
- Designed and replicated unique client's environment to evaluate specific network infrastructure vulnerabilities and security events such as Denial of Service (DoS) attacks.

Key Achievements:

- **IBM Security Systems:** Top-ranked in closing the most support tickets for three consecutive months. Assumed a leadership role on team and trained colleagues in effective troubleshooting and assisted management in interviewing potential hires.
 - Took initiative to develop knowledge base articles, allowing customers to self- resolve common issues and significantly reducing number of support calls.
 - Recommended to management ways to improve the technical expertise of the engineers through industry certification.
- Florida Power & Light: Built a test environment for disaster recovery of SiteProtector Management System, and assisted client in setting it up in their production environment.
- **JP Morgan Chase:** Provided solution to effectively purge and tune the security events entering their SiteProtector Management System database.
- **Bombay Stock Exchange:** Mitigated issue with web servers being attacked and manually filtered out particular IP addresses flooding their servers. Showed client how to slow down and/or absorb attacks using IPS product while keeping their servers functional.
- Dell Secureworks: Tuned security policies on IPS/IDS products to distinguish between benign
 and malicious traffic, preventing malicious traffic from entering the network. Educated client in
 reviewing IPS logs and interpreting if operating conditions were normal or about to fail.

Na Ya Plastics Corporation-America, Lake City, SC, 04/2008 -12/2010

Engineering Project Manager

Directed team of 24 (12 direct reports, 12 external contractors) on internal projects through the lifecycle, from requirements definition to setup, sign-off, and post-support. Performed cost analysis, prepared quotes, ordered equipment, and managed project budgets. Negotiated pricing and vendor contracts.

PROFESSIONAL & COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

PyAtl, Atlanta Ruby Meetup Group, Alpharetta Rails Coders, Atlanta Selenium / Watir Webdriver Meetup, Altanta FullStack, OWASP Atlanta, DEF CON

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Industrial Engineering, Clemson University, Clemson, SC, 2007